John A. Subhan Papers
John A. Subhan Papers
1939-1966
Subhan, John A.
3.5 linear ft.
Papers of the Methodist clergyman; born a Muslim in Calcutta in 1899. Collection includes correspondence, manuscript articles, and clippings about a Methodist bishop in India.
148691
Biographical History
John A. Subhan was born August 8, 1899 in Calcutta, India into a Muslim home, and his early education was in that faith. When he was 11 years old he converted to Christianity and later attended English schools in India. He graduated from Allahabad University in 1923 and went on to earn a B.D. degree in 1931 from Serampore College. In 1962 he received an honorary D.D. degree from Asbury Theological Seminary in Wilmore, Kentucky and another that same year from Serampore College. Subhan taught at St. Peter's College at Agra, the Methodist Theological Seminary at Bareilly, and at the Henry Martyn Institute of Islamic Studies. From 1957-1964 he served as Bishop of the Hyderabad Area. After retiring, Subhan moved to Boston and taught theology at Boston University. He and his wife, Dorothy Sinclair Day, had three children.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The John A. Subhan Papers include biographical material, correspondence, manuscripts, and published material. Correspondence consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence from individuals and organizations in India and elsewhere. Subject files consists of material on various topics, including Anglo-Indian schools, charges against Bishop Subhan, christian marriage, Hyderabad Conference, and Protestantism. Manuscripts contains manuscripts of articles. Published material consists of a newspaper clipping and a newsletter.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject. Manuscripts and Published material are arranged alphabetically by type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Subhan, John A.; Methodist Church -- India.; Clergy -- India.; Methodists -- India.; Correspondence.; Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - A, 1948; 1958-1960,; 1965,; 1966 (Box 1)
  - Ali, Syed Hadi, 1959 (Box 1)
  - American Express Co., Inc., 1960; 1962,; 1963,; undated (Box 1)
  - Arabindo, Bishop, 1961 (Box 1)
  - B, 1947; 1949,; 1950,; 1958-1961,; 1963,; 1964 (Box 1)
  - Balarem, Rt. Rev. Bishop P.C.B., 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin Boys' High School, 1948; 1951,; 1959,; 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - Bhajjan, Dr. S.V., 1962; 1965 (Box 1)
  - Bidar District Situation, 1959-1961 (Box 1)
  - Bombay Conference, 1946-1950; 1954,; 1955 (Box 1)
  - Bryant, H. Noel, 1959; 1960 (Box 1)
  - C, 1948; 1958,; 1959-1966 (Box 1)
  - Christian Book Centre, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Church Union
    - Calcutta, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Foreign, 1959; 1961 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944; 1947,; 1953-1958,; 1960-1963 (Box 2)
  - Council of Evangelism, Mission to Fiji, 1962; 1963 (Box 2)
  - D, 1947; 1948,; 1959,; 1960,; 1962-1964 (Box 2)
  - David, Rev. M., 1957; 1963-1966 (Box 2)
  - Douglas, Ian, 1964-1966; undated (Box 2)
  - Durrani, Rev. M.H., 1944; 1948,; 1950,; 1959-1963 (Box 2)
  - F, 1947; 1959 (Box 2)
  - Foreign
    - 1957-1959 (Box 2)
    - 1960 (Box 2)
    - 1961 (Box 3)
    - 1962 (Box 3)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 3)
    - 1963 (Box 3)
    - 1964, undated (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1957; 1962 (Box 3)
  - Franklyn, T.B., 1963; 1965 (Box 3)
  - G, 1956; 1959,; 1963-1966 (Box 3)
  - H, 1948; 1958,; 1962-1966 (Box 3)
  - I, 1959; 1961,; 1963-1966 (Box 3)
  - J, 1958; 1961,; 1962,; 1964,; 1965 (Box 3)
  - Job, H., 1960 (Box 3)
  - Jones, E. Stanley, 1954; undated (Box 3)
  - Jones, Mr. and Mrs. Frank L., 1958; 1959,; 1961 (Box 3)
  - Jones, Mrs. L. Bevan, 1959; 1960 (Box 3)
  - Joshua, Rev. O., 1953; 1958,; 1963-1965,; undated (Box 3)
  - K, 1947; 1958,; 1960,; 1964,; 1965 (Box 3)
  - Karodi, Rev. J.P., 1959 (Box 3)
  - L, 1947; 1954,; 1957-1959,; 1962-1966 (Box 4)
  - Lacey, Henry A., 1962-1965; undated (Box 4)
  - Leonard Theological College, 1961; 1962,; 1963,; 1964-1966,; undated (Box 4)
  - Local
    - Incoming
      - A-Y, 1957; 1958,; 1963-1965 (Box 4)
      - Methodist Church, 1963; 1965 (Box 4)
      - Unidentified, 1959; 1961,; 1963,; 1965 (Box 4)
    - Outgoing
      - 1956, 1958-1961, 1963-1965, undated (Box 4)
  - Lucknow Publishing Co., 1959; 1961 (Box 4)
  - M, 1949; 1950,; 1959-1966 (Box 4)
  - Mathews, James K., 1952; 1953,; 1957-1960 (Box 4)
  - Mehrotra, B.N., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Mission Hospital Court Case, Bidar I and II, 1959; 1960 (Box 4)
  - Nondol, Bishop S.K., 1953; 1954,; 1957-1964,; 1966,; undated (Box 4)
  - N, 1959; 1963,; 1964,; 1966 (Box 5)
  - Nath, Rev. R.V., 1958-1960 (Box 5)
  - O, P, Q, 1948; 1954,; 1959-1961,; 1963-1966 (Box 5)
  - Paul, Rev. E.B., 1957-1959; 1962-1963 (Box 5)
  - Priestly, Bishop E., 1960; 1961,; 1964,; 1965 (Box 5)
  - R, 1948; 1956,; 1959,; 1962-1966 (Box 5)
  - Raines, Richard C., 1963-1965 (Box 5)
  - Reddy, E.C., 1957-1959; 1960-1062 (Box 5)
  - S, 1939; 1948,; 1950,; 1952,; 1956,; 1958,; 1959,; 1961-1966 (Box 5)
  - Short, Bishop Roy H., 1961; 1962,; 1964-1966 (Box 5)
  - Singh, Bishop Mangel
    - I, II and III, 1959-1964 (Box 5)
    - 1959, 1962-1966, undated (Box 5)
  - Subhan, Eunice, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Sudershanam, Ratna, 1959-1961; 1965 (Box 6)
  - Sully, Ven'ble Dr. T.D., 1958; 1959,; 1961,; 1964 (Box 6)
  - Sumitra, Rev. H., 1958; 1960,; 1961 (Box 6)
  - Sundarem, Bishop, 1958-1965; undated (Box 6)
  - T, 1948; 1949,; 1961,; 1964,; 1966 (Box 6)
  - Taylor, Bishop Prince A., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Tewarson, S.B., 1962-1965; undated (Box 6)
  - U, V, 1949; 1958,; 1964,; 1966 (Box 6)
  - W, Z, 1952; 1959,; 1960,; 1964,; 1966 (Box 6)
  - Whittaker, Rt. Rev. Frank, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Wicke, Bishop Lloyd C., 1964; 1965 (Box 6)
  - Williams, Mrs. E.W., 1959 (Box 6)
  - World Council of Churches, 1963; 1965,; 1966 (Box 6)
  - Unidentified, 1957; 1958,; 1962,; 1963 (Box 6)
- Subject files
  - Anglo-Indian Schools, 1959; 1962,; 1963 (Box 7)
  - Bills, receipts, 1959; 1965 (Box 7)
  - Charges against Bishop Subhan, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Christian marriages, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Church Union, 1949; 1953-1955,; 1957,; 1959,; 1961 (Box 7)
  - Hyderabad Conference, undated (Box 7)
  - Legal documents (copies), 1959; 1964 (Box 7)
  - Meetings, minutes and programs, 1958; 1960,; 1962,; 1964,; 1966 (Box 7)
  - Methodist Boys School, Hyderabad, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Methodist missions, 1961; 1963 (Box 7)
  - Protestantism family tree (Box 7)
  - Reports, 1957-1959; 1961,; 1964,; undated (Box 7)
  - Schedules, 1947 (Box 7)
- Manuscripts
  - Articles on church union, undated (Box 7)
  - Articles, general (Box 7)
- Published material
  - Newsletter, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Newspaper clippings about Subhan, 1959 (Box 7)